Marietta Simpson Collection, 1967-2019 SC 168
Archives of African American Music and Culture
Marietta Simpson Collection
1967-2019
Archives of African American Music and Culture
Simpson, Marietta
SC 168
22 document cases 9.4 linear feet
The collection consists primarily of programs, newspaper and magazine clippings, photographs, scrapbooks, awards, correspondence, memorabilia, posters, clothing, audio recordings and video related to Marietta Simpson's career.
Arrangement
Arranged in ten series:
Series 1: Papers
--- SubSeries 1.1: Professional
--- SubSeries 1.2: Personal
Series 2: Programs
--- SubSeries 2.1: Simpson Programs
--- SubSeries 2.2: Other Programs
--- SubSeries 2.3: Awards & Certificates
Series 3: Press Clippings & Promotional Materials
Series 4: Photographs & Albums
Series 5: Music (Printed and Manuscript)
Series 6: Memorabilia & Realia
Series 7: Clothing
Series 8: Posters
Series 9: Sound Recordings
Series 10: Video Recordings
Biographical / Historical
Marietta Simpson is a renowned American mezzo-soprano with an illustrious music career that spans well over fifty years. Simpson was born in November, 1958 in Philadelphia, PA to Melvin and Evelyn Simpson. The second youngest of eight siblings, Marietta was raised within an exceedingly talented musical family that included her sisters Joy Simpson, the late internationally acclaimed soprano, and Evelyn Simpson-Curenton, composer and pianist. During Marietta's youth, the Simpson family toured as a musical act, the Singing Simpsons, performing both classical and gospel music repertoire. The family strove to break the barriers of what was expected from Black musicians performing in predominantly White communities and churches.
Simpson attended Temple University studying music education with a concentration in trombone and transitioned to voice toward the end of her degree. She earned a masters degree from the State University of New York at Binghamton, studying under Carmen Savoca and Peyton Hibbitt, and made her operatic debut as Mamma Lucia in Mascagni's Cavalleria Rusticana with the Tri-Cities Opera Company. In 1984, after a stint with the Chautauqua summer program, Simpson auditioned for the Houston Opera where she was cast in the role of Maria in Gershwin's Porgy and Bess. In 1985, she auditioned for Robert Shaw as a soloist for the Bach B Minor Mass but was ultimately hired as a soloist in his production of Handel's Messiah. Simpson continued to work with Shaw for the next thirteen years and marks this period as a catalyst for her career. Under Shaw, she also made her Carnegie Hall debut in 1988 as soloist in Brahms' Alto Rhapsody with the Atlanta Symphony Orchestra. Simpson's opera career continued over the next two decades, including performances with many opera companies including Lyric Opera of Chicago, LA Opera, Washington National Opera, and on prestigious international stages such as La Scala, Glyndebourne, and the Royal Opera House at Convent Garden. Simpson has also sung with every major orchestra in the United States, under many of the world's greatest conductors, and with numerous choral ensembles. As a recitalist, she frequently performs spirituals and other works by Black composers, and is often accompanied by her sister, Evelyn Simpson-Curenton.
Simpson began teaching at Indiana University in August 2005, where she earned the title of Distinguished Rudy Professor of Voice in the Jacobs School of Music. In 2019 she was elected as a fellow of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences and also received an IU Bicentennial Medal honoring distinguished and distinctive Service. In 2020 she was named an IU Distinguished Professor. Other achievements include her solo role on the Grammy Award-winning recording of William Bolcom's Songs of Innocence and Experience with Leonard Slatkin conducting, an Emmy award-winning rendition of "Strange Fruit" with guitarist Tyron Cooper, a Temple University Certificate of Honor for Distinguished Alumni and the Leontyne Price Award.
Acces Restrictions
Use of time-based media materials (audio and video) may require production of listening or viewing copies.
Access to streaming audio, moving image, and full resolution digital image materials may currently be restricted to researchers who can authenticate with an IU account or who are physically present on campus. Remote streaming to individual researchers may be allowed with the completion of applicable forms.
For further information about access to online audiovisual materials, contact AAAMC staff at aaamc@indiana.edu.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Marietta Simpson in January and February 2019, and 2020.
Scope and Contents
Series 1 consists of Simpsons professional and personal correspondence and papers. Professional papers include correspondence with managers and performing arts organizations, press kits, travel and tour itineraries, management contracts and schedules, greeting cards from cast members, administrative documents, and materials relating to her teaching career at Indiana University. Personal papers include correspondence with family and colleagues, greeting cards, family wedding, anniversary and funeral programs, and documents related to Simpson's daughter's education.
Series 2 includes various membership and participation certificates as well as awards presented to Simpson in honor of her musical achievements. A small sampling of libretti, sheet music and scores for hymns, spirituals, and operas performed by Simpson comprise Series 3, including music for a television taping of the Time of Deliverance Singers.
Series 4 features biographical articles in magazines and newsletters, as well as press clippings and reviews related to Simpson's recitals and performances. These are further documented in Series 5, which includes programs from Simpson's performances with orchestras and opera companies, as well as recitals, masterclasses, IU concerts and other private events beginning with her high school and college years. Also included are programs featuring Simpson's students and colleagues, and from other performances she attended such as a Maria Callas recital.
Series 6 contains both professional and personal photographs from performances and events, professional headshots, and a photo scrapbook documenting the Temple University Marching Band's trip to the Miracle Bowl in Tokyo in December 1977. There are also many Simpson family historical photographs and multiple photo albums. The majority of the photographs in this series are unidentified.
Series 7-9 includes various memorabilia and realia from Simpson's career, posters and oversize prints, and gowns worn during performances. Audio recordings in series 10 consists of unpublished recordings of Simpson's recitals, rehearsals and performances featuring classical, jazz and gospel music, as well as published CDs featuring Simpson performing classical repertoire, primarily with Robert Shaw.
Both published and unpublished video recordings are included in series 11, featuring Simpson's professional performances in addition to home videos that include performances with other Simpson family members, weddings, and funeral services.
African American women singers; Simpson-Curenton, Evelyn, 1953-
- 1. Papers
  - 1.1. Professional papers and Correspondence
    - Judd Concert Bureau, 1985 (Box: 1, Folder 1)
    - Herbert Barrett Management Brochure, 1990 (Box: 1, Folder 2)
    - Herbert Barrett Management Correspondence, 1992 (Box: 1, Folder 3)
    - Herbert Barrett Management: Bach Choir of Bethlehem "Bach to Germany" Tour, 1995 (Box: 1, Folder 4)
    - Herbert Barrett Management Correspondence, 1992 (Box: 1, Folder 5)
    - Herbert Barrett Management: Simpson Press Kit, 1997-06 (Box: 1, Folder 6)
    - Herbert Barrett Management: Itineraries and Correspondence, 1998 (Box: 1, Folder 7)
    - Herbert Barrett Management: Schedules, Correspondence, Contracts, 2000-2001 (Box: 1, Folder 8-9)
    - Herbert Barrett Management: Press Kit, 2001 (Box: 1, Folder 10)
    - Herbert Barrett Management: Schedules, Correspondence, Contracts, 2002-2013 (Box: 1, Folder 11-22)
    - Glimmerglass Festival contract, 2014 (Box: 1, Folder 23)
    - Herbert Barrett Management: Correspondence, Invoices, 2015 (Box: 1, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence, Temple University, 1978-1981 (Box: 1, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence, auditions, 1986-1988 (Box: 1, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence, Delta Sigma Theta candidacy, 1988 (Box: 1, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence, Delta Sigma Theta candidacy, 1988 (Box: 1, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence and Administrative Documents, 1989 (Box: 1, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence, 1990 (Box: 1, Folder 29)
    - Correspondence, Concerts, 1991 (Box: 2, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence and cards, Royal Opera House Porgy and Bess, 2010 (Box: 2, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence and Administrative Documents, 1992-1996 (Box: 2, Folder 3-7)
    - Correspondence and cards, Bregenzer Festspiele Porgy and Bess, 1997-07 (Box: 2, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence and Administrative Documents, 1997-1998 (Box: 2, Folder 9-10)
    - Correspondence, Lisa Kohler photography (credits for publicity photos), 1998 (Box: 2, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence and Schedules (Box: 2, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence and Greeting Cards, 2000 (Box: 2, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence and Administrative Documents, 2001 (Box: 2, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence and Greeting Cards, 2002 (Box: 2, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence and Schedules, 2003-2006 (Box: 2, Folder 16-19)
    - Correspondence, Indiana University, 2006-2018 (Box: 2, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence and Schedules, 2007 (Box: 2, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence (LA Opera Porgy and Bess), 2007 (Box: 2, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence and Contracts, 2008 (Box: 2, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence and Schedules (Glyndebourne, Eötvös), 2008 (Box: 2, Folder 24-25)
    - Correspondence and Schedules, Opera Theater of St. Louis, 2008 (Box: 2, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence and Schedules (Lyric Opera, Porgy and Bess), 2008 (Box: 2, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence and Schedules, 2009 (Box: 2, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence and Schedules, 2010 (Box: 3, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence and Brochures, Netherlands, 2010 (Box: 3, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence and Schedules, 2011 (Box: 3, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 2012 (Box: 3, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence and Schedules, Houston Grand Opera Show Boat, 2012-2013 (Box: 3, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, Houston Grand Opera Show Boat, 2013 (Box: 3, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence and Schedules, 2013 (Box: 3, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, IU Singing Hoosiers, 2013-10 (Box: 3, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 2014 (Box: 3, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 2015 (Box: 3, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence and Brochures, KZN Philharmonic, Nairobi, Kenya, 2015 (Box: 3, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence and Schedules, Glimmerglass Candide, 2015 (Box: 3, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, Toulouse Candide, 2016 (Box: 3, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence and Greeting Cards, 2017 (Box: 3, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence and Schedules, Vocal Essence, 2018 (Box: 3, Folder 15)
    - Curriculum Vitae, 2013 (Box: 3, Folder 16)
    - Indiana University Tenure and Promotion Dossier, IU Jacobs School of Music, 2008 (Box: 3, Folder 17-19)
    - Schedule Book, 1980 (Box: 3, Folder 20)
    - Schedule Book, 2007-2008 (Box: 3, Folder 21)
    - Address Book (Box: 4, Folder 1)
    - Budget Book, 1991 (Box: 4, Folder 1)
  - 1.2. Personal Papers and Correspondence (primarily related to Simpson family)
    - Correspondence and Thank You Cards, 2005-2019 (Box: 4, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence and Greeting Cards from Colleagues and Students, 2005-2018 (Box: 4, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence and Greeting Cards (Box: 4, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence and Greeting Cards (Box: 4, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, Cynthia Clarey, 1987-1995 (Box: 4, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, Colonton Freeman, 1993-1995 (Box: 4, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence and song text, DW Brykalski, 2019 (Box: 4, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence and Greeting Cards, Simpson Family, 2015-2018 (Box: 4, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, Carol Simpson, 2010-2018 (Box: 4, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, Simpson Family, 2004-2009 (Box: 4, Folder 11)
    - Charlie Robert and Anna Smith Family, 1978-08 (Box: 4, Folder 12)
    - Flyer, Singing Simpsons: A Sacred Concert (Bethany Evangelical United Brethren Church, Palymra, PA), 1967-07-30 (Box: 4, Folder 14)
    - Joy Simpson death certificate, 1987-03 (Box: 4, Folder 15)
    - Joy Simpson death, newspaper clippings, 1987-03-1987-04 (Box: 4, Folder 16)
    - Joy Simpson funeral, 1987-04-01 (Box: 4, Folder 17)
    - Marietta Simpson Wedding, 1991-06-22 (Box: 4, Folder 18)
    - Elder Melvin H. Simpson Sr. Funeral, 1999-05 (Box: 4, Folder 19)
    - Evelyn Smith Simpson Funeral, 2006-04-2006-06 (Box: 4, Folder 20)
    - Evelyn Smith Simpson Family History, 2011 (Box: 4, Folder 21)
    - Adrienne Simpson, High Street Christian Academy, 1991-1992 (Box: 5, Folder 1)
    - Adrienne Simpson, Springside School Directory, 2002-2003 (Box: 5, Folder 2)
    - Adrienne Simpson, Philadelphia "Year of the Child" Celebration, 2004-03-07 (Box: 5, Folder 3)
    - Adrienne Simpson, Springside School Commencement, 2004 (Box: 5, Folder 4)
    - Adrienne Simpson, Friends Forever Story (Box: 5, Folder 5)
    - Adrienne Simpson, Princeton Commencement, 2008-06 (Box: 5, Folder 6)
    - Adrienne Simpson and Andre Gittens Wedding, 2010-07-31 (Box: 5, Folder 7)
    - Adrienne Simpson, Harvard Law School Commencement, 2012-05-23 (Box: 5, Folder 8)
    - Dr. Garth Gittens, Calvary Baptist Church, 2013-2014 (Box: 5, Folder 9)
    - Pastor Sheppard (Box: 5, Folder 10)
    - Passports, Marietta Simpson, 1987-2009 (Box: 5, Folder 11)
    - Philadelphia High School for Girls (Box: 5, Folder 12)
    - Simpson surname printed flyer (Box: 5, Folder 13)
- 2. Awards and Certificates
  - Metropolitan Opera National Council, Regional Finalist: Southwest, 1985-02-17 (Box: 5, Folder 2)
  - Metropolitan Opera National Council, Regional Finalist: Southwest, 1986 (Box: 5, Folder 2)
  - National Association of Negro Business and Professional Women's Clubs, Mid-Atlantic District Vocal Competition, First Place, 1989-06-23 (Box: 5, Folder 3)
  - Philadelphia High School for Girls, Alumnae Association Life Membership, 1996-10 (Box: 5, Folder 4)
  - Pi Kappa Lambda, Eta Eta Chapter honorary membership, 2000-04-28 (Box: 5, Folder 5)
  - National Association of Negro Musicians, Inc.: Certificate of Life Membership, 2007-07-30 (Box: 5, Folder 6)
  - NATS membership certificate, 2009-11 (Box: 5, Folder 7)
  - Celebrating Faculty Women of Achievement: Tenured and Promoted Professors, Promotion to Professor, 2010-03-25 (Box: 5, Folder 8)
  - NANM Certificate of Appreciation, 2011-07-25 (Box: 5, Folder 9)
  - Delta Sigma Theta, Philadelphia Chapter, recognition of 25 years of membership, 2014-05-22 (Box: 5, Folder 10)
- 3. Music and Libretti
  - Den himmelske Lovsang / James R. Murray (photocopy) (Box: 5, Folder 1)
  - Elijah Rock! / Roger Emerson: (pub. Hal Leonard), 1998 (Box: 5, Folder 2)
  - Fanfare for Christmas Day / Martin Shaw (pub. Curwen and Sons), 1922 (Box: 5, Folder 3)
  - Hymnal (cover missing) (Box: 5, Folder 4)
  - Incomplete songs (Box: 5, Folder 5)
  - Let Us Go Back to the Old Landmark / Brewster (pub. Bowles Music House), 1949 (Box: 5, Folder 6)
  - Libretti: Bach: St. Matthew Passion (Shaw Translation); Excerpt from Of Love and Other Demons? (Box: 5, Folder 7)
  - Spiritual compilation (cover missing) (Box: 5, Folder 8)
  - Time of Deliverance Singers (music for television taping), 1981 (Box: 5, Folder 9)
- 4. Newspaper Clippings and Articles
  - Ithaca Opera Marriage of Figaro review, 1982-03 (Box: 6, Folder 1)
  - Temple University Alumni Review, 1979 (Box: 6, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, 1984 (Box: 6, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 1985 (Box: 6, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, 1986 (Box: 6, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, 1987 (Box: 6, Folder 6)
  - Clippings, 1988 (Box: 6, Folder 7)
  - Clippings, 1989 (Box: 6, Folder 8)
  - Clippings, 1990 (Box: 6, Folder 9)
  - Clippings, 1991 (Box: 6, Folder 10)
  - Clippings, 1992 (Box: 6, Folder 11)
  - Clippings, 1993 (Box: 6, Folder 12)
  - Clippings, 1994 (Box: 6, Folder 13)
  - Clippings, 1995 (Box: 6, Folder 14)
  - Clippings, 1996 (Box: 6, Folder 15)
  - Clippings (photocopies), 1997 (Box: 6, Folder 16)
  - Clippings (newspapers), 1997 (Box: 6, Folder 17)
  - Clippings, 1998 (Box: 6, Folder 19)
  - Clippings, 1999 (Box: 6, Folder 20)
  - Clippings, 2000 (Box: 6, Folder 21)
  - Clippings, 2001 (Box: 6, Folder 22)
  - Clippings, 2002 (Box: 6, Folder 23)
  - Clippings, 2003-2004 (Box: 6, Folder 24)
  - Clippings, 2005-2006 (Box: 6, Folder 25)
  - Clippings, 2007 (Box: 6, Folder 26)
  - Clippings, 2008-2009 (Box: 6, Folder 27)
  - Clippings, 2010-2012 (Box: 6, Folder 28)
  - Clippings, 2010-2012 (Box: 6, Folder 29)
- 5. Programs
  - 5.1. Simpson Concerts and Recitals, 1975-2019, undated
    - Schools on Parade (Philadelphia, PA), 1975-04-18 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Fourth Annual President's Concert (Philadelphia, PA), 1977-04-17 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Pro Musica Society of Bucks County presents Temple University Orchestra, 1977-12 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      General
      Water damage and possible mold
    - Haydn, Creation, Philadelphia Orchestra, 1979-02 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Sixth Annual President's Concert, Temple University Symphonic Band, 1979-03-18 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Recital, Presbyterian Church of Morris Plains, NJ, 1979-10-21 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - 51st Anniversary, Association for the Study of Afro-American Life and History, Philadelphia, 1980-09-27 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Mozart: Marriage of Figaro (Marcellina), Ithaca Opera Association, 1982-03 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Symphonic Soul V; Napoleon, Lloyd and Harmon: Pieces of a Dream; Zion Baptist Church (Philadelphia, PA), 1982-05-23 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Bellini: Norma (Adalgisa), Tri-Cities Opera (The Forum, Binghampton, NY), 1982-10 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Master's Recital, Opera Specialization, SUNY-Binghampton Department of Music, 1983-03-18 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Gershwin: Porgy and Bess (Clara), Orlando Opera Company, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Fledermaus Gala (Prince Orlofsky), Chautauqua Opera, 1984-07 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Blitzstein: Regina (Addie), Augusta Opera, 1985-01 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Puccini: Madame Butterfly (Suzuki) and Weil Street Scene (Second Nursemaid) Chautauqua Opera, 1985-09 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Rossini: The Italian Girl in Algiers (Isabella), Tri-Cities Opera (Binghampton, NY), 1987-01 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Gershwin: Porgy and Bess (Maria), Opera Columbus (OH), 1987-01 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Gershwin: Porgy and Bess (Maria), Royal Philharmonic Orchestra (London), 1987-07 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Gershwin: Porgy and Bess (Maria), Glyndebourne Festival Opera (UK), 1987-08 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Duruflé: Requiem, Dallas Symphony Orchestra, 1987-09 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Recital, Concert Artist Series, Austin Peay State University, 1987-11 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Gershwin: Porgy and Bess (Serena), Opera North (Academy of Music, Philadelphia, PA), 1988-06 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Szymanowski: Stabat Mater; Janacêk: Glagolitic Mass, Los Angeles Philharmonic, 1988-11 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Bach: Magnificat; Vivaldi: Gloria; Schubert: Mass in G, Atlanta Symphony Orchestra, 1988-12 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Bach: St. Matthew Passion, Detroit Symphony Orchestra, 1989-03 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - 40th Anniversary Gala, Tri-Cities Opera (Binghampton, NY), 1989-06 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Mostly Mozart Festival; Beethoven: Mass in C Major, Houston Symphony, 1989-07 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Leontyne Price Vocal Artists Competition (Miami, FL), 1989-07-19 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Beethoven Cycle, Bunkamura Hall (Tokyo, Japan), 1989-09 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - J. Strauss: Fledermaus (Prince Orlofsky), Pennsylvania Opera Theater (Philadelphia, PA), 1990-10 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Handel: Messiah, The Handel Society Chorus and Orchestra (Dartmouth College), 1990-02-17 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Bach: Mass in B Minor, Atlanta Symphony Orchestra, 1990-03 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Mendelssohn: Elijah, San Francisco Symphony, 1990-10 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Mendelssohn: Elijah, New York Philharmonic, 1990-12 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Hindemith: When Lilacs Last in the Dooryard Bloom'd (Florida State University), 1991-02-02 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Haydn: Creation, Choral Arts Society of Washington (Kennedy Center), 1991-02-04 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Bach: St. John Passion, Handel and Haydn Society (Boston, MA), 1991-03 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Janacêk: Glagolitic Mass, Philadelphia Orchestra, 1991-07-17 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Ward: The Crucible (Tituba), Chautauqua Opera, 1991-08 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Recital, Ohio Wesleyan, 1992-04-05 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Handel: Messiah, Orchestra of St. Luke's, Atlanta Symphony Chamber Chorus (Carnegie Hall), 1992-04-13 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Beethoven: Missa Solemnis, National Symphony Orchestra (Kennedy Center), 1992-06 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Gershwin: Porgy and Bess (Maria), The Royal Opera, 1992-10-1992-11 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Misha Amory Recital (Alice Tully Hall, Lincoln Center), 1993-04-26 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Bach Choir of Bethlehem Eighty-Sixth Festival, 1993-05 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Dvořák: Requiem, Bard Music Festival, 1993-08-22 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Recital, Matinée Musicale Club (Cincinnati, OH), 1993-10-12 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Verdi: Stabat Mater; Szymanowski: Stabat Mater; Poulenc: Stabat Mater, Atlanta Symphony Orchestra, 1993-11 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Recital, Morris Brown College, 1994-02-06 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Recital, Columbia University, 1994-02-17 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Holcombe: Three Spirituals, Temple University Wind Symphony, 1994-02-25 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Bach: St. Matthew Passion, St. Paul Chamber Orchestra, 1994-04 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Recital, Christian Campers, Inc. and The Senior Choir of Grace Baptist Church (Philadelphia, PA), 1994-07-24 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Brahms: Nänie; Gesang der Parzen; Hindemith: When Lilacs Last in the Door-yard Bloom'd (Carnegie Hall), 1995-01-15 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Tribute to Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr., Philadelphia Orchestra, 1995-01-23 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Gershwin: Porgy and Bess (Maria), Teatro alla Scala, 1995-02-22 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Recital, Weill Recital Hall (Carnegie Hall), 1995-02-24 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Mendelssohn: Psalm 114; Szymanowski: Stabat Mater, American Symphony Orchestra (Kennedy Center), 1995-03-10 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Mahler: Symphony No. 8, Cleveland Orchestra (Carnegie Hall), 1995-05-04 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Choral Music of African-American Composers, 1995-05-06 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Hindemith: When Lilacs Last in the Dooryard Bloom'd, Cincinnati Symphony Orchestra May Festival, 1995-05-26 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Prokofiev: Alexander Nevsky, Baltimore Symphony Orchestra, 1995-06 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Independence Day, Presentation 1995 Philadelphia Liberty Medal, 1995-07-04 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - J. Strauss: Zigeunerbaron (Mirabella), New York Philharmonic, 1995-07 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Bach Choir of Bethlehem (Germany Tour), 1995-07 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Recital, winner of the 1995 Musical Fund Society of Philadelphia Award, 1995-11-28 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Handel: Messiah, Columbus Symphony Orchestra, 1995-12-03 (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Recitals, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - Thompson/Stein: Four Saints in Three Acts (Commère), Houston Grand Opera, 1996-01-1996-02 (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - Bach: Mass in B Minor, New Haven Symphony Orchestra, 1996-02-15 (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - Bach: St. Matthew Passion, Atlanta Symphony Orchestra, 1996-03 (Box 8, Folder 37)